{
    "id": "7ee51b24f7df445c88c2eea809c55d84",
    "title": "General Grammar Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "The train ............................... before we reached the railway station.",
            "description": "We use the past perfect for the earlier of two past actions. ",
            "answers": [
                "left",
                "has left",
                "had left"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "The old man ................................. alone in that hut.",
            "description": "The simple present is used to talk about facts. ",
            "answers": [
                "is living",
                "lives",
                "has lived"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Rani .................................. for a job ever since she left college.",
            "description": "The present perfect continuous tense is used to talk about an action or situation that started in the past and has continued up to the present.",
            "answers": [
                "is trying",
                "has been trying",
                "has tried"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Samuel .................................. two wickets before rain interrupted play.",
            "description": "We use the past perfect for the earlier of two past actions. ",
            "answers": [
                "took",
                "has taken",
                "had taken"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I ................................ him before he left.",
            "description": "We use the past perfect for the earlier of two past actions. ",
            "answers": [
                "met",
                "had met",
                "have met"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I .................................... very hard last month.",
            "description": "We use the simple past to say what happened at a past time.",
            "answers": [
                "worked",
                "used to work",
                "had worked"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I .................................. in Mumbai for 10 years.",
            "description": "The simple past is the most common tense for talking about finished actions or situations. ",
            "answers": [
                "live",
                "lived",
                "had lived"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I ................................... London three times last year.",
            "description": "We use the simple past to say how many times something happened in the past.",
            "answers": [
                "visited",
                "have visited",
                "had visited"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I always ...................................... be afraid of dogs.",
            "description": "We use used to to talk about past habits and states.",
            "answers": [
                "use to",
                "used to"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Heat ................................. bodies.",
            "description": "We use the simple present to talk about facts.",
            "answers": [
                "expand",
                "expands",
                "has expanded"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "We ................................... here since",
            "description": "The present perfect and present perfect continuous can both be used to talk about actions or situations that started in the past and has continued up to the present.",
            "answers": [
                "have lived",
                "have been living",
                "are living"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Did you ................................... him yesterday?",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "see",
                "saw",
                "seen"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        }
    ]
}